

# Abstract
  
The paper will describe the trend towards increased complexity in clinical research and the dissapointing ROI with reduced monitoring models.
This paper will briefly summarize the need for a new frame work for designing data quality surveillance capabilties in risk-based monitoring and quality by design models within the clinical research industry.
This paper will propose a comprehensive end-to-end frame work for designing quality surveillance procedures using a modern data science inspired framework

# Introduction:

## Increased complexity in clinical trials

## Historical methodology and tools

## New E6 guidance

# Methodology

## Project Management Principals
### The PMBOK

## Analytical Maturity

## Basic Principals of Data Science

## Degrees of Intelligence

## Quality Responsibility Distribution

## Sunk Cost Falacy
The inclination towards sunk cost fallacy is intuitive and pervasive.  To add to it's liklihood, convincing managers to give support a project or if one was faced with general skepticism about costs, time, or probability of success would make the optics of later reversing course or abandoning efforts scary or professionally detrimental.
Regardless, it doesn't matter if weeks or months of time or thousands of dollars were dedicated to a project. The only deciding factor as to whether a process, tool, technology, etc should be used is "does it add value?"

Sunk Cost Falacy
	the amount of time/resources put into development of something is not an input into decision to utilize that item
	- only question: does the thing meet our needs.  That's item
	- if the answer is no, 
		- next question is how did we invest so much time into something that doesn't meet our needs?
		Answer: insufficient planning in the design
			- there are people here who are driving design but don't have the experience to do it in a way that supports RBM models
			
## Back Propagation Framework
### Planning Input Layer

### Objective Function

### Definition Layer
#### Contraints
#### Technology
#### User Scope

### Forgotten Layer
#### Knowledge Transfer
#### Monitor and Control
#### Lean
#### Synergy

### Yield Layer
#### Procedures
#### Tools

### Solution Layer


## Examples

## Conclusion




